[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Management is both a process and an _______, meaning it involves systematic approaches to achieving goals and serves as a field of academic study.",
      "answer": "discipline"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "The core management processes in educational institutions include _______, organizing, staffing, controlling, and delegating.",
      "answer": "planning"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "_______ is essential for setting objectives and deciding on the steps to achieve them within educational institutions.",
      "answer": "Planning"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "In the context of education, ________ involves recruiting the right people for specific roles, ensuring they possess the required skills.",
      "answer": "staffing"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "_______ refers to monitoring the institutionâ€™s performance and making adjustments to ensure goals are being met.",
      "answer": "Controlling"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "The historical evolution of management principles began to address the needs of ________ organizations.",
      "answer": "industrial"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "The diversity in Indian society includes differences in culture, language, religion, _______, and educational backgrounds.",
      "answer": "ethnicity"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Rapid technological advancements in education require education management to bridge the gap between students' technological skills and teachers' capabilities, which includes the integration of ________ tools in the classroom.",
      "answer": "digital"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "_______ helps in fostering an inclusive educational environment by ensuring that teaching methods and school policies are responsive to cultural diversity.",
      "answer": "Management"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Education management plays a crucial role in enhancing the effectiveness of educational institutions by ensuring the optimal utilization of ________ such as human resources, physical infrastructure, and knowledge.",
      "answer": "resources"
    }
  ]
  